Guide to the Records of Office of the Chancellor RG.3.0.1
New York University Archives
- Series I
  - Controversy of 1838, 1838 Dec 12-1839 Mar 1 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Newspaper clipping about conditions at the University and early history, 1838 Dec. (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Samuel Reed to NYU; NY Supreme Court, 1838 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Bills and vouchers; schlolarship forms, from a book of certificate forms showing various kinds of receipts for contributions toward scholarship (See: Box 13, folder 2), 1838 (Box 4)
  - Testimony in favor of Dr. Paine; Correspondence including: letter from Archibald Maclay, Assistant Secretary, concerning a resolution of the NYU system of finance; letter from Prof. B. Patton, Librarian, about suggestions for raising library fee, request for salary to be fixed by Council, and resignation from position as Librarian; letter from George N. Schuyler, about library job; letter from Prof. Tappan concerning dues; also Report of the Committee on several Faculties, Report of the Committee on Medical Faculty, Report of the Committee on the Library, and a remonstrance of the senior class against vacating the chair of Natural Philosophy., 1838 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Report of Finance Committee on Scholar- ships; Charles Butler letter of resig- nation from the Chair of Committee on Finance; Report of Committee appointed on communications of Chancellor and Faculty of the University; Report of the Committee on communications of Chancellor and students of University, 1838 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Report to Regents, 1838-1839 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Medical Faculty rent proposals and agreements, 1839 Jan. 9 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Council minutes, 1839 Jan. 18 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - List of life scholarships held in the University, 1839 Feb. 1 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Report of President on completion of mortgage, 1839 Feb. 4 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Memorial of professors and decision of the Regents about the Controversy of 1838, 1839 Feb. 8 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Resignation of a professor (no name given), 1839 Feb. 9 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1839 Mar. 14 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Petition from shareholders of the City of New York concerning the Controversy of 1838, 1839 Apr. 8 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Memorial of the Council to State Senate, manuscript of William C. Noyes, 1839 Apr. 15 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Photocopies of letters to Prof. Proudfit from Robert Kelly including a sketch of the history of the Regent of the University concerning the Controversy of 1838, 1839 Apr. 26 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - W.C. Noyes notes of investigation, handwritten, and a copy and typed transcript of part of these notes with a partial transcription by Theodore F. Jones, concerning the Con- troversy of 1838, 1839 Apr. 26 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Report of the Committee on the election of members of Common Council of the City, 1839 May. (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Dr. Mathews' final account, 1839 Jun. 1 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Photocopy of article in New-York Commercial Advertiser on the inauguration of Mr. Frelinghuysen (See: Box 14, folder 16 for original), 1839 Jun. 7 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Article in NY Daily Express about NYU, 1839 June. 10 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - William H. Seward to William C. Noyes about University's State Prison debt, 1839 July. 2 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Class of 1839, 1839 July. 13 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Invitation to Public Schools to sent student to Commencement, 1839 July. (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - William Seward (?) to George Griswold 1839, 1839 Sept. 18 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - B. Butler to Council, 1839 Sept. 24 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - University to Prof. L.L. DaPonte, 1839 Oct. 1 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Chancellor's Report, 1839 Oct. 30 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Controversy over the resignation of Mathews, 1839 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Notices of trial, 1839 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Bills and vouchers, 1839 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence including: letter from John W. Draper letter to Chairman of the commettee of Free Scholarships; Reports including: Report of Instructors of the Annual University Regulations and Medical Faculty Building; also Memorials of the Committee of Council to Senate; correspondence re payment of debts and faculty compensation, 1839 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Professors' petition to Senate concerning the Controversy of 1838, 1839 [?] (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - William Kent to President of Council, 1840 Mar. 12 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Photocopy of Class of 1844 list [?], 1840 Sept. 21 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Bills and vouchers, 1840 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Literary Societies' Communication to the Council about the Annual Report to Regents; Report of the Chancellor on Number of Undergraduates; also miscellaneous correspondence; grade sheet of Prof. Henry; invitation to attend Annual Oration before the Literary Societies, 1840 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - NY physicians recommendation of Dr. Bedford, 1840 [?] (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Correspondence about Historical Society Library from Dr. Frederic DePeyster, 1841 May. 22 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Chancellor's Report, 1841 Oct. 27 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Grade sheets, 1841 Dec. (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Medical Faculty Reports; also miscellaneous correspondence, 1841 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Class of 1844 list, photocopy of Class Merit Book of University, 1841-1844 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence of the Law Department's Benjamin Butler to Council about inaugural address, 1842 Jan. 25 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Grade sheets; grade sheet of Prof. Henry, Mar. (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - List of paying students, 1842 Sept. 14 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Chancellor's Report, 1842 Oct. 26 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Lists of paying and scholarship students, 1842 Nov. 30 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Mason Endowed Professorship, 1842 Dec. 17 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1842 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Report to Regents, 1842-1843 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Grade sheets, Mar. (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Chancellor's Report, 1843 Oct. 25 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Photocopy of report of the Medical Department Faculty to Gov. Bouck (Original at the NY Hospital-Cornell Medical Center Archives), 1843 Dec. 18 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Report of the Committee on Leading Scholarships, Report of Committee on Professor's salaries, also miscellaneous correspondence; Council resolutions, committee report, letters, 1843 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Class reports, Mar. (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Degrees, 1844; also Chancellor's Report of the Senior Class in Moral Philosophy; invitation to attend Anniversary Celebration of the Eucleian Society; miscellaneous correspondence (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Chancellor's Report of Senior Class, correspondence of Medical Faculty, list of medical graduates and 1845 degrees granted, Report on scholarships; student petitions, letter (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Photocopy of note in NY Tribune about instruction in art (See: Box 14, folder 17 for original), 1846 Mar. 30 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence from W.B. Post, 1846 May. 27 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Annual report of Chancellor to Council, 1846 Oct. 28 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Council Minutes, list of Medical Graduate degrees, resolutions of Faculty of Science and Letters, and miscellaneous correspondence; student petitions, Tallmadge's resignation, bill and vouchers, 1846 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Letter from Gardiner Spring to Legislature of NY, 1847 Feb. 6 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Rebuttal of charges made by James Tallmadge (from NY Daily Tribune), 1847 May. 5 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence from Frelinghuysen; letter, bills and vouchers, 1847 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Report to Regents; Reports on instruction, full report missing, 1847-1848 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Report of Medical Faculty to Council of University, 1848 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Print-out from microfilm of Charles Lanman papers (letter from T. Addison Richards to Charles Lanman about death of artist Thomas Cole), 1848 Feb. 14 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Letter from Frelinghuysen to Charles M. Tomkins, 1849 Jan. 2 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Commencement exercises of June 27, 1849 described in unidentified newspaper; and Charles Butler statement on progress of University, 1849 Jun. 27 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Tenant's agreement for University Building, 1849 Oct. 1 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Flyer concerning subscription, 1849 Nov. 26 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Chancellor's Report (full report missing), 1849 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Correspondence and reports about Prof. C. Mason, 1849 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Correspondence of Charles Butler concerning debt, 1850 Feb. 22 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Charles Butler memorandum (with notes) (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Endowed professorships, 1850 Mar. 13 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Financial statement, 1850 Oct. (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Correspondence including a letter from Draper to Noyes; resolutions adopted at annual meeting of Association of Alumni; financial statement of the University as prepared by Prof. Johnson, Assistant Treasurer; bill (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - William R. Martin to Chancellor Ferris? (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Van Schaick to C. Butler, 1850-1851 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Petition requesting dismissal of George Anthon (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Private circular from Medical Faculty to members of Council about graduation fees; memorial of medical faculty to Council asking to be relieved from paying graduation fees to University; and correspondence, 1851 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Resolutions of Council; copy of S.F.B. Morse letter to E. Loomis (original Morse letter at Yale), 1851-1852 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Correspondence to Ferris about appointment, 1852 Jan. 5 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Published statement of Finance Committee, 1852 Jun. (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Photocopy of a Memoranda of facts in relation to University service, 1852 Oct. (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Photocopy of extract from Council Minutes about Ferris, 1852 Nov. 24 (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Photocopy of notice of Ferris' election, 1852 Dec. 10 (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - Photocopy of Ferris' remarks on accepting appointment, 1852 Dec. (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Correspondence; letters, financial report, lists, 1852 (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Report of Council to Regents, 1852-1853 (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Lists of professorships or other office held and salary; student list from Prof. Crosby, Clerk of Faculty; lists of faculty courses and reports by faculty of J.W. Draper to W.C. Noyes, 1852-1853 (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - Letter regarding adoptions at a Council meeting, 1853 Jan. 5 (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - Ferris' address at public meeting (from NY Herald) (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - Bills and vouchers, 1853 Mar. 8 (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - Photocopy of commencement article in NY Herald (See: Box 14, folder 18 for original), 1853 Jun. 30 (Box 5, Folder 59)
  - Ferris to Council about issues acted upon at Council meeting, 1853 Sept. 26 (Box 5, Folder 60)
  - National Magazine-Education, 1853 Sept. (Box 5, Folder 61)
  - Ferris' notes about George Adler (Box 5, Folder 62)
  - Photocopy listing of "Philosophic Instruments Stolen", 1853 Oct. 6 (Box 5, Folder 63)
  - Flyer with Ferris reference to Evening Faculty, 1853 Oct. (Box 5, Folder 64)
  - Printed sheet of rules of order and discipline; University financial matters, committee reports, Ferris' regulation from Dutch Reform Church, 1853 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1853 Jan.-1853 Jun. (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1853 Jul.-1853 Dec. (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Report to Regents, 1853-1854 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Bills and vouchers, 1853-1854 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - S.F.B. Morese to Myndert Van Schaick, 1854 Jan. 19 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Commencement lists for class of 1854, 1854 Mar. 6 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - German professorships, applications and testimonies, 1854 Mar -1855 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - S.F.B. Morse to Chancellor Ferris (oversize box 14, folder 21), 1854 Apr. 17 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Ferris' notes about the janitor (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Article from NY Daily Tribune about Literary Societies, 1854 Jun. 26 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Commencement expenses, 1854 Jun. 28 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Photocopies of invitations to Open House, 1854 Sept. 10 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Telegraphic Development (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Article from NY Daily Times about Medical Department opening, 1854 Oct. 16 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Photocopy of NY Mirror article about the University, 1854 Nov. 10 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, 1854 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence with Ferris, 1854 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous material relating to Ferris administration, 1854 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Report to Regents, 1854-1855 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Bills and vouchers, 1854-1855 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Miscellaneous; clippings, council resolutions, statistics on enrollment and income, notes, 1854-1855 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Photocopies of Resolutions of Alumni concerning Ferris, 1855 Jun. 27 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence including: ordination testimonial from Belfast Presbyterian, letters about honorary degrees, letter from Mason about honorary degree, and a memorial on behalf of Doctor of Music recommending Lowell Mason; clipping about University commencement, notes for a plan of union of the University and the Free Academy, 1855 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Report to Regents, 1855-1856 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Henry P. Tappan to Charles Butler, 1856 Feb. 11 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Benjamin Butler correspondence about history of law instruction, 1856 Jul. 8 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Joseph Henry to Isaac Ferris, 1856 Oct. 29 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Chancellor's Report, 1856 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Minutes of the Council, 1856 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Bills and vouchers, 1856 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Report of Medical Faculty to Council and correspondence including: letters from Elias Loomis and Howard Crosby; also printed working plan for the formation of a University; resolutions of the Board of Rutgers Female Institute, Grammar School Report, letters; note from Francisco Gonzales to Prof. Richard H. Bull regarding Diploma of Civil Engineering, 1856 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Report to Regents, 1856-1857 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Bills and vouchers, 1856-1857 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Photocopy of letter from Elias Loomis to Isaac Ferris, 1857 Jul. 24 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Chancellor's Report, 1857 Oct. 26 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - S.F.B. Morse to Isaac Ferris, 1857 Nov. 17 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Minutes of Council, 1857 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Medical Faculty minutes; Report of Finance Committee; Report of Committee on Elections; and correspondence, 1857 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Report to Regents; photocopy of a printed list of professors and instructors at the University (See: Box 14, folder 19 for original), 1857-1858 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Bills and vouchers, 1857-1858 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Greek studies, 1857-1858 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Plan of the Law School, 1858 May. 27 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Henry Tuckerman to Ferris, 1858 Jun. 29 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 1858 Jul. 28 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Chancellor's Report, 1858 Oct. (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Photocopy of newspaper article on achievements of Chancellor Ferris (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - J.W. Draper to Ferris The University Item, Vol. 1, no. 1 (See: LD 4, drawer 12), Nov. 4 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Memorial of the Law Faculty concerning the Library; also correspondence; letters, clippings, 1858 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Report of studies for the yera 1857-1858 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Photocopy of message to the Class of 1839?, 1859 Apr. 11 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - A. Oakey Hall to Howard Crosby, 1859 Aug. 1 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Ferris to Henry Baird, 1859 Aug. 13 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - R. Baird to Ferris concerning H. Baird, 1859 Aug. 17 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Photocopy of advertisement of large Chapel, 1859 Sept. (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Letter from Maurias Theophilus Aptonay [?], 1859 Oct. 1 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence including: letters from Prof. Howard Crosby, Charles Butler, and D. M. Halliday; receipts, clippings, announcement of space available in Univ. Hall, letter, 1859 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Report to Regents (See also: Box 13, folder 4 for the Catalogue of the University of the City of New York, 1860, from the Chancellor's Desk), 1859-1860 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Bills and vouchers; receipts for faculty salaries, 1859-1860 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - List of Law Department Graduates, 1859-1863 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Photocopy of letter from A. Boardman Lambert to Chancellor Ferris, 1860 Jun. 19 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Photocopy of letter from Elias Loomis to Isaac Ferris, 1860 Sept. 24 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Chancellor's Report, 1860 Oct. 10 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Medical Faculty Minutes; Report of the Faculty of Law; and correspondence including letters from Faculty of Arts and Sciences to the Council of the University and correspondence of Frelinghuysen; letters of recommendation about Ferris for position of Provost at the University of Pennsylvania, 1860 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Report to Regents, 1860-1861 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Bills and vouchers (with information about salaries), 1860-1861 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Chancellor's Report, 1861 Oct. 23 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence; list of names of students recommended for LL.B.; Report on Honorary Degree citations; and list of degrees conferred at the 1831 commencement, 1861 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Report to Regents, 1861-1862 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Bills and vouchers (with information about salaries) Regents' Reports for year ending Sept 1861 through year ending Sept 1869 (See: Box 13, folder 5), 1861-1862, 1861-1869 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Chancellor's Report, 1862 Oct. 28 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Bills and vouchers (with information about salaries), 1862 Oct-1863 Oct (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Photocopy of S.F.B. Morse letter to Mrs. Alfred Vail, 1862 Nov. 17 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence and Regents comments on Military organization; letters, Ferris' analysis of a book, 1862 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Report to Regents, 1862-1863 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Chancellor's Report, 1863 Dec. 7 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - List of names recommended for degree from the Law Department, 1863 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Minutes of the Council, 1863 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Bills and vouchers (with information about salaries), 1863 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence; Minutes of Medical 1863 Faculty Meeting; recommendations for special honorary degrees; and list of degrees to be conferred in 1864 by the Medical Faculty; letters (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Report to Regents; Report on instruction (full report missing), 1863-1864 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Law Department lists of candidates for Bachelor of Laws, Mar. (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Law Department correspondence, resignation of Prof. Wedgewood, and Report of Committee to investigate Commencement, May. 11 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence of Abbott, Benjamin to Noyes which include views on legal instruction at University, 1864 July. 8 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Report of the Committee to consider the condition of the Law Dept.; pro- posed course of law study; and Report on Committee on Reorganization of the Law Faculty, 1864 Aug. 3 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence, John Johnston to William R. Martin, 1864 Sept. 21 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Request from George J. Adler to use University Building for lecture, 1864 Oct. 10 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Chancellor's Report, 1864 Oct. 19 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Photocopy of printed report to the Regents, 1864 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    Custodial History
    As of July 2024, the contents of this folder are missing.
  - Bills and vouchers (with information about salaries), 1864 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence; list of degrees conferred by Medical Dept.; extracts from minutes of the Faculty (various meetins); Report of Committee on Honorary Degrees; list of awards and prizes at Commencement of 1864; letters (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Report to Regents: Report on Instruction (full report missing), 1864-1865 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Class cards of the Medical School, 1864-1865 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Facsimile of Alumni Committee fund raising letter signed by Howard Crosby, Henry M. Baird and R. Ogden Dormus (?), 1865 Jan. 15 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Letter of John W. Draper to Council, 1865 Feb. 27 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Facsimile of Endowment Committee letter signed by John Taylor Johnston, John C. Green, James Brown, William E. Dodge, George Griswold, and William M. Vermilipe, Council members, 1865 Mar. 20 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Letter of Thomas Clarke to Ferris, 1865 Apr. 4 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Chancellor's Report, 1865 Oct. 17 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Minutes of the Council, 1865 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Bills and vounchers (with information about salaries), 1865 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence of William Van Norden, J.J. Stevenson, Tallmadge, H. Loomis, D. Gillette, Cornelius Roosevelt Duffie, Thomas S. Hastings, Thomas Evans, Andrew Stevenson, William Allen Butler, and Dr. Draper's letter about Medical Degrees, 1865 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Report to Regents (full report missing) The University Item, N. 111 (Removed to LD4, Drawer 12), 1865-1866, Mar.1, 1866 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Draper Report about Medical School fire, 1866 May. 25 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Chancellor's Report, 1866 Oct. 16 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Loring Andrew's Gift, 1866 Oct. 18 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence of J.W. Draper, George W. Bacon, Morris K. Jesup, Mr. Woolworth, F.A.P. Barnard, Edward Octavius Flagg, Charles D. Cleveland, and Elias Loomis; clippings announcing the new degree in engineering being conferred by the University, announcement of endowment, 1866 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Law Department to the Council of the University on its condition, 1866 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Minutes of the Council, 1866 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Bills and vouchers (with information about salaries), 1866 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Report to Regents, 1866-1867 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Law School Council report of those who will receive their degrees and lists of their names, 1866-1867 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Report to Regents, 1866-1867 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Law School Council report of those who will receive their degrees and lists of their names, 1866-1867 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Letters of Alfred H. Guernsey to Ferris, May. 10 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Letter from T. Addison Richards to Ferris, 1867 May. 24 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence including letters of George W. Clarke, Prof. Drisler, William R. Martin, George Griswold, Charles Butler, and Henry Draper; also resignation of Prof. J.W. Draper and nomination of Dr. H. Draper in the Medical Department; Medical Faculty communication; Treasurer's Report; Medical Faculty degrees; resignation of Prof. Cummings; list of Commencement awards; Report of Inspectors of Election; Report of Committee on Chancellor's recommendation; and Finance Committee Report; letter, 1867 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Rent Roll of the Old University Building at Washington Square, 1865-1866 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Minutes of the Council; Annual Reports of Finance and Commerce; Annual Statement of the Chancellor; Report of Committee on Honorary Degrees; and list of Honorary Degrees, 1867 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Bills and vouchers (with information about salaries), 1867 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Report to Regents: Reports on instruction (full report missing), 1867-1868 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Letter from George Comfort to Ferris about, 1868 June. 1 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - W.S. Tyler to Howard Crosby, 1868 June. 10 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Photocopy of letter from S.F.B. Morse to Chancellor Ferris, 1868 June. 17 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Chancellor's Report, 1868 Oct. 22 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence including: Mr. E. Collin, Prof. Richards, Edward S. Bunker, J.H. Duryea, Remington F. Randolph, and Samuel R. Forman; also Report on Honorary Degrees; Honors at Commencement; Librarians Report; and Report of Committees on Election; list of commencement awards, 1868 (Box 10, Folder 8)